# Resume



Mohammed Moinuddin

## **Profile Summary**

Able to manage the provision of targeted psychosocial support (e.g. recreational and psychoeducation activities) to children, adolescent and caregivers. Special focus on particularly vulnerable groups, including women and children, survivors of violence, and youth displaced from regular educational activities.

Have the ability to manage and guide a team.

Experienced in HR and communication.

## **Address:**

Plot No: #13, Shah Amanot Housing Society, 1 kilometer, Chittagong.

Cell No: 01852-398130, 01954972331.

#### E-mail:

moinuddinchisty72@gmail.com Skype ID: chisty72

# INFORMATION

Father : Payar Mohammed
Mother : Rokeya Begum
Date of birth : 15 Feb, 1994
Marital Status : Single
NID 778 906 4321

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# Child Protection Officer (Psycho-Social Support- PSS) – August 2020 to Continuing

Danish Refugee Council, Cox's bazar, Bangladesh.

#### TASK/ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Providing individual and group psychosocial counseling to the refugee, beneficiaries and host community at the multi-purpose hub and also in field.
- Asses the psychosocial cases, document the cases and monitor them until recovery.
- Provide referral of beneficiaries for additional assistance as needed, to internal and external service provider.
- Provide structured psychosocial support sessions to children adolescents and caregivers.
- Helped to develop the structured psychosocial support module for beneficiaries.
- Leading as an Child Protection Focal point (CPFP) from sub-sector in camp to provide better services.
- Provide training to staffs and volunteer to understand better assessment of psychosocial support.
- Submitting daily, weekly and monthly report to the line manager.

Psycho Social Support Officer (PSS OFFICER) –(July 2018 to December 2019) Terre des homes, Cox's bazar, Bangladesh

## TASK/ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Conduct session with Children, Adolescent Caregivers.
- Awareness session with the Imam, Majhi, Caregivers regarding how to treat their Children, Women, Girls, Community and also how to take care of Disable children.
- Conduct different activity and monitor their improvements.
- To refer beneficiaries with special needs or at risk, and follow up the referred cases conditions in collaboration with the child protection assistant, team leader and case management team.
- Assessment and support for all beneficiary cases and monitor them until recover
- Coordinate with other PSS officers and dovolunteer's assessments and capacity building assessment.
- Updates the PSS TL on the project process or on any modifications that that need to be taken regarding the implementation process.
- Maintain and strengthen the relations with the other organization dealing with Child Protection and psychosocial support. Daily, weekly and monthly report to the TL

Sales Staff – (2015 to 2016) Pebbles (Clothing Brand) 2 no gate, Baizid Bostami Road, Chittagong.

#### Job Responsibilities:

- Selling the clothing product
- Perform Marketing Strategy
- Customer Service

#### SKILLS

- Conflict Resolution
- Team player
- Time Management
- Interpersonal skill
- Soft Skill

- Team Leadership Skill
- Multi-tasking
- Computer Skill
- Task Delegation

## ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

MBA with HR from Southern University Bangladesh in year 2020 with CGPA 3.46 out of 4.0

**BBA** with HR from Southern University Bangladesh in year 2018 with **CGPA 3.31 out of 4.0** 

# TRAINING & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Training on Gender Based Violence (GBV)
- Training on Psychological First Aid (PFA)
- Workshop on Disability in Emergency
- Youth Leadership In Community Social Work
- Advanced MS Excel from New Horizons CLC

**Internship ON Human Resource Management** (January 2018 to March 2018)

Mas Intimates Bangladesh Pvt. Ltd.

#### Personal Achievement

- CTG Division Basketball Player (Present From2010)
- Volunteer in JOBMARKETBD.COM (Career Talks & Career planning)
- Participated at Entrepreneurship Fair 2017 Organized by Department of Business Administration, Southern University Bangladesh.
- Professional Basketball Trainer (CJKS).

## REFERENCES

Name: Noor -E- Elahi Name: Taqib Ul Islam Chowdhury.

Position: CBP Team Leader Position: Protection field officer
Org: Danish Refugee Council Cell: +8801725566996 Cross

Cell: +8801725566996 Email: noore.elahi@drc.ngo

ail: noore.elahi@drc.ngo Cell: +8801742318978 Email: tchowdhury@icrc.org